

NIKITA SHEVCHUK Front-end Developer ♥ Kyiv, Ukraine

Email: <a href="mailto:shevchuk.nikita.gh@gmail.com">shevchuk.nikita.gh@gmail.com</a>

**Phone:** +380931471176

**Github:** github.com/NikitaShevchuk **LinkedIn:** www.linkedin.com/in/mykyta-

shevchuk-404928251/

Portfolio: nikitashevchuk.github.io/portfolio

# **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Software engineer with experience in building web apps with React, Next.js, Node.js, Django, and Typescript. Can easily communicate in English during a workflow. My passion is building dynamic, content-aware client-facing systems for online retail, business services, and other areas with a modern tech stack.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Develops Today April 2023 - May 2024 (13 months)

- Created and maintained a comprehensive marketing platform, increasing user satisfaction by 40%, by developing the UI using Next.js, directly communicating with users to gather feedback, and implementing requested functionality. Improved client onboarding success by 50% by conducting onboarding meetings, maintaining the project, fixing bugs, and developing APIs using Django and Rest Framework. Integrated OpenAI and third-party APIs, and created and maintained a Chrome extension, significantly enhancing platform capabilities.
- Developed a fully functional NFT marketplace platform, by implementing UI development
  with Typescript and Next.js, integrating blockchain interactions, and creating functionalities
  for NFT collections with pipelines to process large amounts of NFTs. Enhanced marketplace
  usability and user satisfaction by implementing advanced filtering and sorting mechanisms
  leading to a 35% increase in user engagement. Developed comprehensive marketplace
  analytics features.
- Managed a team of intern developers, assigning tasks and reviewing their code to ensure quality and consistency with project requirements.
- Conducted technical interviews, effectively recruiting and assessing the technical skills of potential candidates, thereby strengthening the development team.

Freelance June 2020 - December 2021

- Developed a resource for publishing and downloading articles and books in different formats.
- Provided an online service to a customer for searching and managing different schools and courses for children using Wordpress.
- Deployed more than 10 sites on HTML/CSS, Javascript, and WordPress.

#### **SKILLS**

**Front-end:** JavaScript, Typescript, React.js, Next.js, Redux, Redux Toolkit, MUI, Tailwind.css, Tailwind Material, HTML & CSS (SASS, SCSS); **Back-end:** Python, Node.js, Express.js, Nest.js, Django; **Databases:** MongoDB, Postgresql; **Other skills:** Git, Unit testing, E2E testing, Docker, GitHub Actions;

# **EDUCATION** 2019 - 2023

National Taras Shevchenko University of Kyiv (Optical and Mechanical College) Software Engineering

#### **COURSES**

- React The Complete Guide (incl Hooks, React Router, Redux) by Maximilian Schwarzmüller udemy.com (58 hours)
- The Complete JavaScript Course 2022: From Zero to Expert! by Jonas Schmedtmann udemy.com (69 hours)

# **LANGUAGES**

English - Upper-Intermediate (B2), Ukrainian - Native